Pintu Swain







PROFESSIONAL BACKGROUND:

Expert in customer supports with 2+ years of experience in customer supports. Have gained good exposure to understand various aspects of client and customer requirement and providing quality care for ultimate customer satisfaction and proven ability to establish and maintain excellent communication and relationships with clients and my enthusiasm in handling social complaint and escalation data and maintaining the daily report in google sheet including excel advance functions, advance knowledge in MySql and knowledge of outlook and MS Application.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

NoBroker(Bengaluru):

Relationship Executive-18/11/2022- 10/05/2024

Ability to handle multitask and handling the multiple lead simultaneously including high number of calls and chat and tickets and mails with in TAT and my key strengths handling the escalation calls and maintain the google sheet and excel sheet and draft modification and my enthusiasm ability to interact with customers in a professional and courteous manner.

Axis Bank (Bengaluru):

Relationship Executive-05/2022- 10/2022

Strengthened client partnerships by performing hands-on needs assessment and quickly resolved processing and service level issues and contributed positively to bottom line by up-selling value-added service includes gift cards, loyalty programs to existing accounts and providing timely resolution to the customer complaints/grievances.

Gj Solutions India Pvt Ltd (Hyderabad):

Customer care executive (07/2019-03/2020)

Professional and personable customer supports with good communication skills and handling inbound calls for telecom companies and dedicated to customer service representative and proven ability to establish and maintain excellent communications and relationships with clients.

PROJECT:

Acquisition Analysis:

Analyzing the data based on acquisition data and show the total sales. total profit, total cost, total quantity, profit margin and created tables on top customer, top product and profit margin on product and created matrix table, stacked area chart, bar chart and area chart

Technology Used- Power BI, Excel

Sales Performance Analysis:

An e commerce company ran a marketing campaign to generate sales. Company given the data on the type of device each customer used, the sales amount, total transaction for each day etc. Created dashboards on sales analysis by KPIs, category and sub category on discount and profit etc.

Technology Used-Tableau, Excel

SKILLSET:



INTERESTS:



CERTIFICATIONS:

- PGDCA from NIRMATA
- Tableau Certificate at Naresh IT(HYD)
- Data Analyst at Simplilearn
- Business Analytics with Excel At Simplilearn
- Master in Business Analyst At Ineuron

SOFT SKILLS:

- Problem-solving
- Fast Learning
- Time management
- \triangleright Team Player
- **Decision Making**
- Customer Issue
- \triangleright **Escalation**
- Drafting
- Solution-Oriented

EDUCATION BACKGROUND:

> B. Tech, VITAM, Berhampur

2014 – 2018 CGPA-7.39

> +2 Science, G.K.V

Mahavidyalaya, Subalaya

2012 – 2014 Score- 52%

> Matriculation, Khandadeuli High School, Khandadeuli

2011 – 2012 Score- 61%

ACTIVITIES:

- > Participated in inter-college Counter Strike.
- > Participated in college tournament.
- > Participated in inter college volleyball tournament.
- > Participated in inter college basketball.
- > Active blood donor.

LANGUAGE:

- > English
- > Hindi
- Odia

Personal Details:

Name- Pintu Swain Mob- 9777125356

Email-pintuswain3166@gmail.com

DECLARATION:

I hereby declare that all the above-mentioned information is true to the best of my knowledge.